

# **Ben Magyar**

- 254 W State St, Doylestown, PA 18901

#### **A**BOUT

I'm a full-stack software developer who is currently working at NextGen. I've spent the past four years working on improving an analytics and regulatory platform for healthcare providers across the country. Outside of my life as a developer, I enjoy experimenting in the kitchen and coffee.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **NextGen Healthcare**

Horsham, PA

Software Developer

July 2013 - Present

- Rebuilt analytics and regulatory platform, converting from ASP.NET WebForms to WebAPI, React and Redux
- Developed performant and customizable reporting framework atop React and Redux
- Visualized and constructed in-application search engine to reduce documentation lookup times for users
- Introduced and guided development team on unit-testing, test-driven development and automated acceptance testing
- Implemented repeatable, reliable and scalable builds for a multi-tenant solution for thousands of targets
- Developed and maintained services and databases for the regulatory platform
- Conducted database performance evaluations for large-scale relational databases on complex queries
- Mentored and lead team in JavaScript standards and practices established minimum code standards across multiple teams
- Pushed cross-team development forwards by helping to introduce a single package source and build setup for in-house libraries
- Lead team of developers and testers as a scrum master within an agile development process
- Collaborated with project management on the product's direction and aided in rapid proof-of-concept delivery
- Helped support engineers in prioritizing, resolving and fast-tracking issues faced by clients on a rolling basis

#### **American University**

Washington, D.C.

October 2012-May 2013

Research Assistant

- Aided in research in Harmonic Analysis, specifically in reconstructing periodic data in a sparse data set
- Conducted exploratory research in microtiming of musical notes using edge detection in MATLAB, among a group of three students

# **EDUCATION**

**SKILLS** 

# **American University**

Washington D.C.

August 2009 - May 2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Magna Cum Laude

**PROFICIENT** 

